CAREN CHIBWARA Software Developer

Graduate Mechanical Engineer

carrienjiru40@gmail.com 0720031052

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated and analytical professional with a certificate in software development and a Bachelor's degree in Mechanical Engineering. Certified in Siemens Mechatronic Systems (Level 1 and 2), bringing a solid foundation in systems engineering, problem-solving, and automation as well as knowledge on ERP systems. My passion for technology is deeply rooted in a desire to create impactful solutions that drive sustainability and combat climate change. Combining a strong engineering background with software skills, I am keen to apply my expertise to create impactful software solutions within a forward-thinking development team.

EDUCATION

Software Development Certification Moringa School,

February 2024 - August 2024

Bachelor of science in Mechanical Engineering Dedan Kimathi University of Technology, Second Class Upper Division

May 2018 - May 2023

Siemens Mechatronic Systems Certification SITRAIN

- Digital Industry Academy, Level 2

February 2023 - June 2023

High School Diploma Matuga Girls High School, B+Grade

2014 - 2017

WORK EXPERIENCE

 Sales and Design Engineer Intern Universal Kazan, Istanbul, Turkey July 2023 - September 2023

Design Engineer
Centre of Biomass and Energy Research
Dedan Kimathi University of Technology
October 2022 - June 2023

 Mechanical Engineering Inspector County Government of Kwale, October 2021 - January 2022

SKILLS

ERP Systems:

Microsoft Dynamics 365 ERP system **Programming Languages:** Python,

JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks & Libraries: React.js,

Flask

Databases & ORM:

PostgreSQL,SQLAlchemy

Design Skills: Figma, Solidworks,

Siemens NX, Material UI

Tools & Technologies: Git, RESTful

APIs, MS Office

Soft Skills:

Effective Communication, Team Collaboration, Detail-oriented Problem-Solving, Leadership, Time Management

LANGUAGES:

English (Fluent), Kiswahili (Native)